# **Jef Blocker**

689 Rosalia St. SE, Atlanta, GA 30312

(404) 593-1370 l jef@jefblocker.com l www.jefblocker.com

# **ABOUT**

Former project manager with client-focus turned UX designer who is passionate about contributing to a creative team with my diverse skills to produce a satisfying and effective experience that meets the needs of end users while exceeding their expectations.

### **SKILLS**

User Experience I Information Architecture I Interactive Design I Project Management I Wireframing I Prototyping I Results & Feedback Analysis I Client Relations I Axure RP Pro I InVision I HTML 5 I CSS3 I JavaScript I Adobe Illustrator I Adobe Photoshop I Microsoft Office I Google Docs

### **UX DESIGN EXPERIENCE**

**Springboard** – San Francisco, California September 2016 - November 2016 *UX Design Workshop Student* 

I learned user centered design & design thinking, user research, lean UX, content strategy, designing for mobile, sketching, wireframing & prototyping; visual design; and research evaluation by completing real-life projects while working with an expert mentor who is working in the industry.

# **Projects**

BookRapport - Research | Digital Prototype

Researched, designed, created, and tested digital prototype for social app for book clubs.

# PROGRAMMING EXPERIENCE

**The Iron Yard** – Atlanta, Georgia September 2015 – December 2015 Front End Engineering with JavaScript & MVC Frameworks Student Over the course of 12 weeks, learned the ins-and-outs of front end engineering using HTML, CSS, JavaScript and basic server-side tech to create beautiful, fully functional websites and web applications

### **Projects**

Movie Sidekick - Repo I Demo

Created a social media app that allows users to search movies and post reviews using the Open Movie Database (OMDb) API. I contributed to the conceptual planning, naming, design, and coding using AngularJS

Classic Science Fiction Posters - Repo I Demo

Created an app with AngularJS that allows a user to add images to an online database. Users also have the ability to make a red heart appear when they click on an image to "like" it. A counter displays the number of likes for each image

MTV Classic Music Videos - Repo I Demo

Remember when MTV used to play music videos? I designed this app with ReactJS as a tribute to the golden age of MTV. The app gives users the ability to view, add, and edit images to a database.

# **Jef Blocker**

689 Rosalia St. SE, Atlanta, GA 30312 (404) 593-1370 l jef@jefblocker.com l www.jefblocker.com

# PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

**Easter Seals North Georgia**, **Inc.** – Atlanta, Georgia May 2010 – September 2015 *Human Resources / IT Specialist* 

Recruited staff and coordinated IT services for 13 locations on behalf of this organization serving children, many with disabilities and special needs

**Bound To Be Read Books** – Atlanta, Georgia September 2005 – May 2015 *Store Manager* 

Hand-sold books, hired & trained staff, scheduled & promoted events, and designed & maintained website

**Atlanta Intown Mortgage** – Atlanta, Georgia March 2005 – May 2010 *Lending Specialist* Originated and processed residential lending loans for Georgia residents

# **EDUCATION**

Certificate of Completion in UX Design, Springboard, 2016

Certificate of Completion in Front End Engineering with JavaScript & MVC Frameworks, The Iron Yard, 2015

Associate of Arts in Multimedia & Web Design, The Art Institute of Atlanta, 2001

Bachelor of Arts in Communications, The University of Texas at Arlington, 1991